A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Humanities and the Arts, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of Wilson McNeil Lowry FA582
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches and Writings, 1955-1974; V
  - Remarks at the Dedication of the New Arena Stage, Washington, D.C., Oct 9, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - "Ford Foundation Program in Contemporary Opera," Opera News (published article), Dec 6, 1961 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - "The Ford Foundation and the Creative Arts," Los Angeles, CA, Jan 10, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "The University and the Creative Arts," Educational Theatre Journal (published article, reprinted by FF), May 1962 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - "The Role of the Arts and the Humanities" by Lowry and Gertrude S. Hooker, American Assembly Report on International Educational and Cultural Exchange, Aug 24, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Remarks at the Dedication of the Ohio University Fine Arts Building, Athens, OH, Nov 9, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "The Ford Foundation and the Creative Arts," North Carolina State Art Society Meeting, Raleigh, NC, Dec 5, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - "The Arts and Philanthropy," Poses Lecture Series, Brandeis University, Waltham, MA, Dec 10, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - "How Are the Arts Best Supported?" Pomona College Symposium, Claremont, CA, Feb 21, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - "The Commitment to Culture and the Arts," 46th Annual Meeting of the American Council on Education, Washington, D.C., reprinted in The Educational Record, Winter 1964 (published article), Oct 2 - Oct 4, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - "The Foundation and the Arts," Manhattan School of Music Symposium, New York, NY, Nov 11, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - "The Arts in Today's Society," MENC Biennial Meeting, Philadelphia, PA, reprinted in Music Educators Journal (published article), Mar 13, 1964 - Mar 17, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Remarks at Commencement, Juilliard School, New York, NY, May 29, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - "The Contemporary University: The Arts," Daedalus (submission for publication), Mar 1965 (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - "The Resident Professional Theatre," Transcript of Background Interview for NET, Jul 1, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - "Art and Intensity," The Martha Graham Convocation, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, Aspen, CO (reprinted by the FF), Jul 30, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - "Opportunities for Philanthropy in the Arts," Conference of Southwest Foundations, Houston, TX, Apr 14, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - "The University and the Creative Arts: II," First Annual Fine Arts Festival, Edwardsville, IL, Apr 16, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Studio Area Theatre Conference Tape Transcription, Buffalo Theatre Conference, Buffalo, NY, Apr 21, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - "National Foundation on the Arts and Humanities: Part I - National Endowment for the Humanities," Statement, Joint Open Hearing of the Senate Special Subcommittee on Arts and Humanities and the House Special Subcommittee on Labor, Washington, D.C., Jul 12, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - "Community Objectives in the Arts," (Transcript, Verbatim), The Arts in Missouri Conference, Columbia, MO, Oct 2, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - "The Arts in Education," Bank Street College of Education at New FF Headquarters Building, New York, NY, Dec 9, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Commencement Address, Minneapolis School of Art, Minneapolis, MN, May 3, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Houston Chronicle Article on Nina Vance (submission for publication), Oct 1968 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "The Economic Crisis in the Arts: The Need for a National Policy," from the Ford Foundation 1968 Annual Report, Nov 1968 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - "The Milieu Crisis in the Arts," Delos Symposium, 1969 Athens Ekistics Month, Athens, Greece, Jul 15, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "The Role of Foundations in the Arts and Humanities," draft (unpublished) Written for Encyclopedia of Education, Aug 1969 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - "This Moment in the Arts," New Alley Theatre Dedication, Houston, Texas, Reprinted in Forum Magazine (published article, reprinted by FF), Summer 1969 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - "National Endowment for the Humanities," Statement to House Committee on Education and Labor, February 4, 1970, Feb 4, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Transcript of Testimony Before House Select Subcommittee on Education (unedited draft), Feb 4, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Presentation of Association of American Dance Companies Award to Roger L. Stevens, Jun 5, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Century Club Board of Management Retirement Speech, Dec 16, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - "Comparisons with a Large Foundation," Chapter from The University as an Organization, Carnegie Commission (published article), Jun 1971 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Excerpts from Testimony at Hearings of the Select Subcommittee on Education on the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities, Mar 20, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Speech to Central Opera Service, New York Sheraton Hotel, New York, NY, Oct 15, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Comments on FF programs in music, Chairmen/Presidents Meeting of Association of Independent Colleges of Music, Juilliard School, New York, NY, Oct 30, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - "On Bearing Witness," (role of arts and humanities) Association of College, University and Community Arts Administrators, New York, NY, Dec 16, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Speech on Role of Arts to the Maryland Institute, Baltimore, MD, Apr 28, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - "The Arts and the Society," Jo Tyler Lecture, University of Missouri at Kansas City, Kansas City, MO, May 7, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - "Notes on the Economics of Music," Duke University, Durham, NC, Oct 18, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Notes for Arden House Talk on Museums, American Assembly, Harriman, NY, Nov 1, 1974 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Ylvisaker, Paul N., Address, Comments on Urbanization, 1963 Citizen's Conference on Community Planning, Indianapolis, IN, Jan 11, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 28)
- APPENDIX A: Reports, 1959-1971
  - Ackley, Gardner, Richard Ruggles and George Stocking, Report to the Ford Foundation on the National Bureau of Economic Research, 1959 (Report 19450)
  - Atwater, Verne S., Report of Study of Ford Foundation Salaries and Benefit Policies, 1965 (Report 19448)
  - Balmer, Donald G., Jean C. Graham and Bernard C. Hennessy, The Coro Foundation: Report of Evaluation and Recommendations, 1962 (Report 19468)
  - Barnett, Jr., Vincent M., Report to the Ford Foundation on SVIMEZ and the Center for Studies on Economic Development, 1962 (Report 19488)
  - Berea College, South Appalachian Studies: An Evaluation, undated (Report 19475)
  - Berger, Morroe, Report on the Non-Western Program of the Atlanta University Center, 1963 (Report 19485)
  - Bergmann, Ralph H., Harold L. Wilensky and Marshal L. Scott, Report of Consultants on the Union Leadership Program at the University of Chicago, 1961 (Report 19449)
  - Campbell, Alan K, Evaluation Report of Grant Program for Student/Faculty Research in Public Affairs, undated (Report 19480)
  - Catalano, Richard M. and Konrad Kellen, University of Oklahoma Urban Science Program, 1964 (Report 19452)
  - Cater, Douglass, Developing Leadership in Government: A Report on the Brookings Executive Conferences, 1960 (Report 19477)
  - Dressner, Howard R., Travel and Study Awards: Information Paper, 1967 (Report 19490)
  - Ehle, John and Peter Marris, Possible American Uses of the Ombudsman System of Scandinavia and the Citizens Advise Bureaus of Britain, 1965 (Report 19460)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz and Albert Christ-Janer, [Report on the Tamarind Lithography Workshop in Los Angeles], 1962 (Report 19451)
  - Esser, George H. and Gilbert Yale Steiner, A Report on Community Studies, Inc., 1959 (Report 19479)
  - Fano, Robert, Laurence Heilprin, Meyer M. Kessler, Lee Loevinger and William Pincus, Report on Visit to the Project on Applications of Computer Techniques to Legal Research at the University of Pittsburgh, 1962 (Report 19469)
  - Fleishhacker, Jr., Mortimer, LaMar T. Empey and Schneider, Evaluation of Carson Pirie Scott-Chicago Board of Education Project, April 1962 (Report 19473)
  - Gil, Federico G., Report to the Ford Foundation on the Asian Studies Program of Lynchburg College, Randolph-Macon Woman's College and Sweet Briar College, 1962 (Report 19486)
  - Gil, Federico G., Report to the Ford Foundation on the Denison University Asian Studies Program, 1959-1962 (Report 19487)
  - Hearle, Edward F. R., Have We Learned Anything from Transportation Studies?, 1963 (Report 19454)
  - Herzberg, Donald G., The Legislative Internship Program: Alaska, California, Hawaii, Illinois, Kansas, Oklahoma, Washington, 1962 (Report 19472)
  - Herzberg, Donald G., The Legislative Internship Program: New York, Indiana, and Michigan, 1962 (Report 19471)
  - Hurd, Charles P. and John M. Mullins, A Review and Evaluation of the Activities of Educational Facilities Laboratories Incorporated, 1965 (Report 19447)
  - James, Bernard J. and Bernard C. Hennessy, Evaluation of Ford Foundation Supported Activity of the Institute for Political Education, Morgan State College, 1962 (Report 19470)
  - James, Gilbert, Evaluation of Fox Valley Urban Extension Program, Wisconsin, undated (Report 19482)
  - Jensen, Glenn S., Activity and Summary Report: The University of Wisconsin Fox Valley Urban Program, 1963 (Report 19481)
  - Kellen, Konrad, A Visit to ACTION - Housing in Pittsburgh, March 9-13, 1964 (Report 19453)
  - Lippitt, Ron, Al Reiss and Red Stephenson, Report of Visit to Syracuse Youth Study Center, 1961 (Report 19455)
  - Lippitt, Ron, Al Reiss and Red Stephenson, Report of Visit to USC Center, 1961 (Report 19456)
  - Metropolitan Community Studies, Inc., Metropolitan Community Studies Program - Dayton, 1959 (Report 19478)
  - Naftalin, Arthur, Evaluation of Citizenship Clearing House Program, 1960 (Report 19476)
  - Pincus, William, The Public Affairs Program, Law Schools, and the Administration of Justice (draft), 1964 (Report 19459)
  - Sheldon, Richard C., University of Wisconsin Urban Extension Program: Executive Summary, 1964 (Report 19483)
  - Sutton, Francis X., The Ford Foundation and Europe: Some Basic Issues and Choices, 1971 (Report 19491)
  - Vernon, Raymond, [Report on the Athens Technological Institute], [1962] (Report 19489)
  - Wadsworth, Homer C., Report on 1962 Visit with the Southeastern Michigan Metropolitan Community Research Corporation (Report 19474)
  - Wadsworth, Homer C., PENJERDEL (Pennsylvania-New Jersey-Delaware Metropolitan Project Incorporated), 1962 (Report 19457)
  - Wadsworth, Homer C. and Charles E. Curran, Evaluation of the Southeastern Michigan Metropolitan Community Research Corporation, 1961 (Report 19458)
  - Whitman, Robert H., Report to the Ford Foundation on the Center of Non-Western Studies at the University of Vermont, 1963 (Report 19484)
  - Winnick, Louis, Long Island University Urban Affairs Conference (speech), 1964 (Report 19461)
  - Winnick, Louis, Rental Housing Problems for Private Investment (speech), 1963 (Report 19465)
  - Winnick, Louis, Social and Economic Questions in Urban Transportation (speech), 1963 (Report 19463)
  - Winnick, Louis, Technological Changes in Urban Transportation (speech), 1963 (Report 19467)
  - Winnick, Louis, The Current Status of City Planning: Prescription v. Public Choice (speech), 1963 (Report 19466)
  - Winnick, Louis, The Planner Looks at Poverty and Race -- Or Does He? (speech), 1963 (Report 19462)
  - Winnick, Louis, Toward a More Livable Urban Environment, 1963 (Report 19464)
  - The Foundation and Western Europe, 1950-1970, 1971-1975 (Report 19492)
  - USSR and Eastern Europe: Foundation Policy in the 1970s, undated (Report 19493)